Guide to the Foggy Bottom Restoration Association records, 1954-1985 MS2159
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Foggy Bottom Restoration Association records
1954-1985
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Franzen, Margaret
MS2159
0.25 Linear Feet
Collection contains correspondence, agendas, a questionnaire, a report, and newspaper articles from 1954-1985 documenting the history of the Foggy Bottom Restoration Association.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
This material was donated to Gelman Library by Margaret Franzen in 1985.
Historical or Biographical Note
The Foggy Bottom Restoration Association had as its mission to promote the restoration and rehabililtation of Foggy Bottom and to further the civic, cultural, social, and economic welfare of the community. The original constitution set the minimum boundaries as 24th Street, 27th Street, K Street, and Virginia Avenue. The first election for executive committee members was June 1955. The original founding members included Carolyn Casper, Jean Robitscher, Paul Flint, Alice Flint, Rose McKee, Elizabeth Wharton, Margaret Franzen, Mr. and Mrs. Dutch, and Peter Glickert.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection contains correspondence, agendas, a questionnaire, a report, and newspaper articles. These materials date from 1954-85 with the bulk dates being 1954-56. These materials tell the history of the Foggy Bottom Restoration Association.
Alleys; Foggy Bottom (Washington, D.C.); Urban renewal; Foggy Bottom Restoration Association (Washington, D.C.); Franzen, Margaret; Glickert, Peter
- Historical information about Foggy Bottom Restoration Association, 07/07/1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Foggy Bottom Restoration Association: Agenda, 11/16/1955 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Foggy Bottom Restoration Association: Agenda, 04/05/1956 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Foggy Bottom Restoration Association: Letter, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence to Evening Star from P. [Peter] Glickert, 01/22/1956 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- The origin, purposes, and growth of the Foggy Bottom Restoration Association, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Proposed Constitution, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- No Slum in Ten Years A Workable Program for Urban Renewal, 10/1954 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Foggy Bottom Taxpayer's Protective Association advertisement, 01/16/1956 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Foggy Bottom is being renewed: Spot Zoning for Commercial Uses Will Not Help the Area, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Ten questions and answers regarding urban renewal in Foggy Bottom, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Newspaper article: "City's Foggy Bottom Seen Test Ground of Urban Renewal" Sunday Star, 10/23/1955 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Newspaper article: "Foggy Bottom Owners Beaten in Slum Fight" Washington Post, 04/11/1956 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Newspaper article: "Fog Has Returned to Foggy Bottom" Washington Post and Times Herald, 11/04/1956 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Newspaper article: "Green Grows the Hose" Washington Post, 06/18/1967 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Newspaper article: "Foggy Bottom is quiet, safe - and expensive" The Mail Tribune, 09/06/1979 (Box 1, Folder 16)